[{"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abff", "question": "In which US state would you find Devils Tower?", "answer": "Wyoming", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a7", "question": "In what fictitious town does \"Invasion of the Body Snatchers\" take place?", "answer": "Hicksville, USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395dd", "question": "Which \"Simpsons\" character has a superfluous third nipple?", "answer": "Krusty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6b0", "question": "What group of chemicals is responsible for the heat in chili peppers?", "answer": "Capsaicinoids", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b79d", "question": "Which chess piece can only move diagonally?", "answer": "The bishop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a193", "question": "Which famous voice-over artist played Woody Woodpecker in his first few cartoons?", "answer": "Mel Blanc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5b466ce05a3942286e14", "question": "\"V-Bucks\" are the in-game currency for which famous videogame franchise?", "answer": "\"Fortnite\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5662b33a95c66dc4fe760", "question": "Mentu is the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7bdef877e98cb9777895b", "question": "What mountain is nicknamed the \"Savage Mountain\"?", "answer": "K-2", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4afd49076251badbeabf", "question": "What was the first food to be intentionally microwaved?", "answer": "Popcorn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e70", "question": "What fictional village sits in the shadow of Mount Crumpit?", "answer": "Whoville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f4e", "question": "Which Saturday Night Live cast member played the Land Shark?", "answer": "Chevy Chase", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd6a38a6c0f9723ab15cb4e", "question": "As of 2020, how many popes have there been?", "answer": "266", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad4", "question": "Who sculpted Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Gutzon Borglum", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bae2", "question": "How many candles are on a menorah?", "answer": "9", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1ce", "question": "In 1986, a brittle O-ring seal was determined to be the cause of what?", "answer": "The Challenger disaster", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe90a3c01dd7bf43be5e898", "question": "An octopus can fit through any hole larger than its what?", "answer": "Its beak", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2f", "question": "Choreographer and actor Chris Judd was what actress and singer's second husband?", "answer": "Jennifer Lopez", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd753e347d002c297e4c1", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e9", "question": "What was writer and war hero T.E. Lawrence popularly known as?", "answer": "Lawrence of Arabia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6f9", "question": "What martial art's name means \"way of the sword\"?", "answer": "Kendo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "60172cff44491cbd7c5a177e", "question": "Who commanded the American troops during World War I?", "answer": "General John J. Pershing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdfa", "question": "Besides aces, what was the other pair in Wild Bill Hickok's \"dead man's hand\"?", "answer": "Eights", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefbe906ce05a3942286ef3", "question": "Who recorded the song \"Lyin' Eyes\"?", "answer": "Eagles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601219dd63c99d48cd169afc", "question": "What is a haboob?", "answer": "A type of sand storm", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c90d18552800b05cac20f12", "question": "Monrovia is the capital of what African country?", "answer": "Liberia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd40", "question": "Who has been the pole sitter at a record six Indy 500s, from 1979 to 1991?", "answer": "Rick Mears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339de2", "question": "What \"Desperate Housewives\" creator broke into TV as a personal assistant to actress Dixie Carter?", "answer": "Marc Cherry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe77302eec85e375820b303", "question": "What is Antarctica's largest island?", "answer": "Alexander Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ec53fe83fe1f2a824bff", "question": "On what day do Orthodox Christians celebrate Jesus' birthday and thus Christmas?", "answer": "January 7th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339260", "question": "What is the stage name of Reginald Kenneth Dwight?", "answer": "Elton John", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c59", "question": "Who was the faithful wife of Ulysses in Homer\u2019s \"Odyssey\"?", "answer": "Penelope", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fef92cd6ce05a3942286e87", "question": "Which famous actor was orginally offered the role of Tommy Williams in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6003958357a0e35c43f83894", "question": "What is the term for reproducing a texture by laying paper over it and rubbing it with a pencil or crayon?", "answer": "Frottage", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a806", "question": "What is the capital of Hungary?", "answer": "Budapest", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd72", "question": "What is sinology the study of?", "answer": "China", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59049a0bcf93664eb1048697", "question": "The Queensland nut is another name for what nut?", "answer": "Macadamia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77f", "question": "What country\u2019s capital is Montevideo?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "60160138fe83fe1f2a824c5c", "question": "Which mainstream fashion magazine was the first to use real photographs?", "answer": "Baron Adolph de Meyer was hired in 1913 to shoot portraits of models, actresses, and aristocrats for Vogue magazine.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59067f74ff9c0647b50a8084", "question": "On what date did the 2016 Dyn Cyberattack take place, rendering some of the largest Internet services unusable for several hours?", "answer": "October 21, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b7ffb533a3a814d89068c64", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Long Walk to Freedom\"?", "answer": "Nelson Mandela's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd48", "question": "In soccer, how many yellow cards lead to a player's disqualification?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c743", "question": "What is the more common term for amblyopia?", "answer": "Lazy eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5909cb7dbb53d1af658864d8", "question": "What band released a single in 1977 entitled \"Father Christmas\"?", "answer": "The Kinks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe766b5eec85e375820b287", "question": "Captain Henry Morgan used what island as a base of buccaneer operations?", "answer": "Jamaica", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfd", "question": "What year did the movie \"Dirty Dancing\" made its debut?", "answer": "1987", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fbaebc10738315b1fb74e2c", "question": "What Shakesperian play involves love between a Roman Soldier and the Queen of Egypt?", "answer": "Antony and Cleopatra", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a6e520565ad31a57c7e1", "question": "What was the last battle of the American Revolution?", "answer": "Battle of Yorktown", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fefc1c76ce05a3942286f15", "question": "What was Luke Skywalker's original name?", "answer": "Like Starkiller", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5990f88efa5fdd6dd25324ee", "question": "How many Great Lakes are there?", "answer": "Five", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac16", "question": "What is the capital of the Seychelles?", "answer": "Victoria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db6", "question": "In what ominous numbered room is Winston Smith strapped to a chair at the end of \"Nineteen Eighty-Four\"?", "answer": "Room 101", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63b", "question": "What did Nestle freeze dry in 1938 that led to the development of powdered food products?", "answer": "Coffee", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba03", "question": "What type of race is the Preakness Stakes?", "answer": "Horse race", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339304", "question": "In the movie \"Indiana Jones and the Temple of Doom\", what is the nickname of Indiana's young sidekick?", "answer": "Short Round", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a19e", "question": "Who sang \"You Can Call Me Al\"?", "answer": "Paul Simon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59220151a4edfd43a087adda", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Dreams From My Father\"?", "answer": "Barack Obama's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd664a5a5bfecdd737e0857", "question": "How many people survived the Titanic sinking?", "answer": "706", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ed2", "question": "What was the subtitle of the 1993 sequel to \"Hot Shots\"?", "answer": "Part Deux", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad1c", "question": "Where was Ben Franklin born?", "answer": "Boston, Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ca", "question": "What is the capital of Arizona?", "answer": "Phoenix", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5a4a94bc61d1b4d384d5d671", "question": "Who is Dana Elaine Owens more commonly known as?", "answer": "Queen Latifah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c87c", "question": "What chemical element has an extra syllable in its more correct British pronunciation?", "answer": "Aluminium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395eb", "question": "In The Simpsons, what kind of footwear does Grampa usually sport?", "answer": "Slippers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394bd", "question": "What was the name of the nightclub that Peter Gunn frequented?", "answer": "Mothers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59e80685de59ea584496feb2", "question": "In which US city would you find the Space Needle?", "answer": "Seattle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3a1", "question": "What birds are traditionally used as gas detectors in coal mines?", "answer": "Canaries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a30f", "question": "Who sang the 1979 song \"Family Tradition\"?", "answer": "Hank Williams Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6df", "question": "What US territory includes the islands of Saint Croix, Saint John and Saint Thomas?", "answer": "US Virgin Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe765e6eec85e375820b279", "question": "What US state's flag has different images on the front and back?", "answer": "Oregon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7a6", "question": "What color is the supposedly cursed Hope Diamond?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb40365ff7d326b622a83", "question": "What year was Budweiser first introduced?", "answer": "1876", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339969", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what grade does Edna Krabappel teach?", "answer": "Fourth grade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a024", "question": "What is the name of the arrogant male co-anchor of Channel 5 News in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Tom Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ff8", "question": "What is composer Vivaldi's first name?", "answer": "Antonio", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58c8a55e90aac110e4167073", "question": "To make beer, what is barley normally made into?", "answer": "Malt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6996a20565ad31a57c746", "question": "In the Bible, who sold his birthright because he was hungry?", "answer": "Esau", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cd505e347d002c297e4b3", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Last of the Mohicans\", first published in 1826?", "answer": "James Fenimore Cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cea", "question": "What singer took his stage name from a Dublin hearing aid billboard?", "answer": "Bono", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e72ce4cd0874f1a5e2d1c27", "question": "Which prominent US statesman was known as \"The Great Compromiser\" and helped allegedly swing the 1824 election?", "answer": "Henry Clay", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5cd40b9e685cf15b733e988a", "question": "In which county in the United Kingdom is the Glastonbury Festival held?", "answer": "Somerset", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068190ff9c0647b50a8095", "question": "Which Gabor sister, who passed away in December of 2016, was crowned Miss Hungary in 1936?", "answer": "Zsa Zsa Gabor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a176", "question": "Who directed the film \"The Bridge on the River Kwai\"?", "answer": "David Lean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3cf", "question": "What area of the Atlantic is said to be responsible for the disappearance of ships and aircraft?", "answer": "Bermuda Triangle", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b748364247bf200fb870", "question": "What is the atomic number for Hydrogen?", "answer": "1", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a4", "question": "What director died four months before the release of his movie \"Eyes Wide Shut\"?", "answer": "Stanley Kubrick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948f", "question": "How long did the 1929 Academy Award ceremony last?", "answer": "15 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c71", "question": "What year was Sylvester Stallone born?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b8d", "question": "What love\u00adstruck Warner Brothers cartoon character often chased a black cat named Penelope?", "answer": "Pepe Le Pew", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388e4", "question": "Which popular musician co-wrote the song \"I'm afraid of Americans\" with David Bowie?", "answer": "Brian Eno", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b160", "question": "What title was Mother Teresa given by Pope John Paul II after her death?", "answer": "Blessed Teresa of Calcutta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1ab", "question": "In the world of music how is \"Harry Lillis\" more commonly known?", "answer": "Bing Crosby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d77", "question": "What was formed by the five robot lions of the planet Arus?", "answer": "Voltron", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b638", "question": "When an entree is prepared \"en brochette\", how is it served?", "answer": "On a skewer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4c5", "question": "What year marked the appearance of Doc Savage?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f95b2ca55722f97b22684df", "question": "What color was Obi-Wan Kenobi's Lightsaber?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a376", "question": "What is the capital of Sweden?", "answer": "Stockholm", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5d", "question": "Clarence Darrow was coaxed out of retirement to defend what famous duo?", "answer": "Leopold & Loeb", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0d", "question": "In the Tom Petty song \"Free Fallin'\", the girl is a big fan of what singer?", "answer": "Elvis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a26", "question": "Whose \"Small House\" is the subject of the play acted out during \"The King and I\"?", "answer": "Uncle Thomas'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3e0", "question": "What creature has the world's largest eyes?", "answer": "Colossal Squid", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac79", "question": "During which American period did stock car racing gain most of its popularity?", "answer": "The Prohibition", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339120", "question": "What year saw the release of H. G. Wells' \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "1895", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95c", "question": "The Purple Heart is awarded for which reason?", "answer": "For wounds received by enemy action while on active service", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ca0", "question": "What famous work did Michelangelo begin in 1508 and complete in 1512?", "answer": "The painting of the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff25b9c31a458464a93c479", "question": "What do people hang over their doors on New Year\u2019s Eve in Greece?", "answer": "Onions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c54e", "question": "What digit does not exist in Roman Numerals?", "answer": "Zero", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa8", "question": "\"A bushy, bushy blonde hair\u00addo\" is a line from what hit song?", "answer": "Surfin' USA", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ed43e06d244b1771b64500d", "question": "In what year was the Solidarity union founded in Poland?", "answer": "1980", "category": "History"}, {"id": "5909cf7abb53d1af658864f4", "question": "In the film \"Home Alone 2\", what city was the McCallister family planning on vacationing in?", "answer": "Miami", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec86bcec223966ae8f8811", "question": "Who was the first female artist in history to have 4 consecutive singles from one album reach the Top 5 in the Billboard Hot 100?", "answer": "Cyndi Lauper's 1983 classic \"She's So Unusual\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7f9", "question": "What is the surgical knife called an \"izmel\" used for?", "answer": "Circumcision at a bris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa8f", "question": "What is the capital of Dominica?", "answer": "Roseau", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fecc30dec223966ae8f887a", "question": "Cricket stars Clyde Walcott, Everton Weekes and Frank Worrell were all born in which city within 18 months of each other?", "answer": "Bridgetown, Barbados", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c952", "question": "The angel shark is commonly referred to by what other name?", "answer": "Monkfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015de7afe83fe1f2a824b6b", "question": "What military leader spread Greek culture from his native Macedonia to the Indian subcontinent?", "answer": "Alexander the Great", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339231", "question": "Who wrote the \"Pink Panther\" theme music?", "answer": "Henry Mancini", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb50", "question": "What does the abbreviation ROI stand for in the financial world?", "answer": "Return on Investment", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbd", "question": "What Hollywood legend made his screen debut in 1961's \"Splendor in the Grass\"?", "answer": "Warren Beatty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfd", "question": "In which movie did Veronica Lake portray a witch?", "answer": "I Married a Witch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6d7", "question": "What is the end opposite the nose called on a snowboard?", "answer": "Tail", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9daf9e748bb36357acdd6", "question": "What is the name of the bony covering over the gills of ray-finned fishes?", "answer": "Operculum", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a279", "question": "What was the birth name of actress Betty Grable?", "answer": "Elizabeth Ruth Grable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b01f", "question": "What was the last name of husband and wife Julius and Ethel, executed for treason in 1953?", "answer": "Rosenberg", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fdffd141cf6db9ac4808d08", "question": "Which country built an airport that only landed one commercial aircraft?", "answer": "United Kingdom", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e65", "question": "Who provided the original voice for SpongeBob SquarePants?", "answer": "Tom Kenny", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c27d", "question": "What animals lives in a lodge?", "answer": "The beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea31ccff048f679a45aae5", "question": "How many eggs does a queen bee lay per day?", "answer": "2000", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea8312ff048f679a45ac25", "question": "What is the speed of sound in air?", "answer": "343 meters per second", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fede45f6ce05a3942286ddd", "question": "Who penned the classic songs \"Bad Moon Rising\", \"Who'll Stop The Rain\", and \"Lodi\"?", "answer": "John Fogarty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b419", "question": "What was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer Empire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4ac", "question": "Which country were the 1952 Winter Olympic Games held in?", "answer": "Norway", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a502", "question": "What are the first four digits of Beverly Hill' zip code?", "answer": "9021", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f1694af7c52aae91cc07cf", "question": "Which 1868 novel is often considered the first full length, English language detective novel?", "answer": "The Moonstone", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338aa2", "question": "What musical won the Tony Award for Best Musical in 1996?", "answer": "Rent", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "594d05821a1c922dd1ac64a3", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad2f", "question": "Who was the sadistic commander of the HMS Bounty?", "answer": "Captain Bligh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c97f", "question": "What constellation is represented by scales?", "answer": "Libra", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17c", "question": "How old was politician Pierre Trudeau when he died in the year 2000?", "answer": "80", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a5", "question": "What nation was led by Peter the Great?", "answer": "Russia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bebc", "question": "What's the first of Elizabeth Kubler-Ross' Five Stages of Grief?", "answer": "Denial", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cb", "question": "Who played the female lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfa6", "question": "The King in chess can move a maximum of this many squares?", "answer": "Two", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5904a3b3cf93664eb10486bf", "question": "Who created the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\"?", "answer": "Terry Moore", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58f167aff7c52aae91cc07bc", "question": "What country borders the Republic of Guinea-Bissau to the south and east?", "answer": "Guinea", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c51", "question": "Who defected from a Leningrad ballet troupe in 1961?", "answer": "Rudolf Nureyev", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bed0", "question": "What game of chance was originally called \"Beano\"?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7c2cd877e98cb9777898e", "question": "Which country set a new Guinness World Record for steepest street in 2019?", "answer": "Wales", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133938e", "question": "Who played the role of Jim Stark in the movie \"Rebel Without a Cause\"?", "answer": "James Dean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c65", "question": "What duo published the story of \"Hansel & Gretel\" in 1812?", "answer": "The Brothers Grimm", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b65b", "question": "Upon his death, what convicted killer donated his corneas?", "answer": "Gary Gilmore", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a441", "question": "Which ancient site in the mountains of Peru is known as \"The Lost City of the Incas\"?", "answer": "Machu Picchu", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58d47103f8e329de4f877897", "question": "What is the brewery featured in the British soap opera \"Coronation Street\"?", "answer": "Newton and Ridley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4b38f06d333868d34d6d9", "question": "Which song produced a Christmas truce during World War I?", "answer": "\"Silent Night\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca6a", "question": "What rare Earth element is the second most abundant one in the known Universe?", "answer": "Helium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7d0", "question": "What is a turkey stuffed with a duck stuffed with a chicken called?", "answer": "Turducken", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5990af62b72eedf883a8c706", "question": "Which US state is known as the \"Mother of Presidents and the Mother of Statesmen\"?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59e6bcf3fb6c85e9e634ff63", "question": "Dakar is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "Senegal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b370d21c3f17ccc40c8e19", "question": "Under the English 1830 Beer Act, what was the cost of the licence to sell beer and cider from your own home?", "answer": "2 guineas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c25", "question": "Which movie was Charlie Chaplin's last?", "answer": "A Countess from Hong Kong", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b928", "question": "What color is the smoke announcing the election of a new pope?", "answer": "White", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ade", "question": "In 1996, what action star was named a \"sacred vessel\" of Tibetan Buddhism?", "answer": "Steven Seagal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b943", "question": "Who was the first boxer to win the world heavyweight championship 3 times?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f6e77a9e54d890926f6c5", "question": "What Caribbean record does the Dominican Republic hold?", "answer": "Highest mountain peak - The highest peak in the Caribbean, Pico Duarte, soars 10,417 feet above the trees.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2e7", "question": "When did actor W. C. Fields die?", "answer": "1946", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b505", "question": "What two skills make up the winter biathlon?", "answer": "Cross-country skiing and target shooting", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c86f", "question": "Enzymes from the papaya fruit are used to make what kitchen staple?", "answer": "Meat tenderizer", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594fb9a8210241017090b57e", "question": "What year did the interval act \"Riverdance\" debut at the Eurovision Song Contest?", "answer": "1994", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf22", "question": "The use of astronomical phenomena to predict earthly and human events is called what?", "answer": "Astrology", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d8c", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is James Smith?", "answer": "LL Cool J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "596dfd6b9616e6c6d4eba4f5", "question": "What country was the first to send an object to the Moon?", "answer": "The Soviet Union", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a644", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Buckeye State\"?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aac", "question": "What actress played Jane in the 2005 remake of the movie \"Fun with Dick and Jane\"?", "answer": "Tea Leoni", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1ed", "question": "What cocktail is considered the official cocktail of New Orleans?", "answer": "Sazerac", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c791", "question": "What continent has the highest native population of cheetahs?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6007823abd51d85e222ab655", "question": "How did the Mus\u00e9e Picasso in Paris come to own its collection of Picasso's works?", "answer": "Since he left no will, his\u00a0death duties\u00a0to the French state were paid in the form of works from his personal collection.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64c", "question": "A duck-billed platypus is one of the only three mammals in the world that can do what?", "answer": "Lay eggs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc8562fabc30a8194e188b0", "question": "In the film \"The Right Stuff\", who played the role of Chuck Yeager?", "answer": "Sam Shepard", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398bb", "question": "Who is Mufasa's son in Disney's movie \"The Lion King\"?", "answer": "Simba", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8f4", "question": "What country borders both of the world's only two nations with square flags?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fca", "question": "What TV show featured the fictional band \"Jesse and the Rippers\"?", "answer": "Full House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbf4", "question": "What Japanese company was responsible for publishing the game Space Invaders?", "answer": "Taito", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2d", "question": "Someone who raises false alarms is said to cry what?", "answer": "Wolf", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b06a", "question": "Terry Nichols was the co-conspirator in what major crime during the 1990\u2019s?", "answer": "Oklahoma City Bombing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf51", "question": "What toy was released in 1958 creating an instant craze among children?", "answer": "The Hula Hoop", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b47b", "question": "When did the Battle of the Plains of Abraham take place?", "answer": "1759", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c10b", "question": "By which name is Paul Francis Gadd better known?", "answer": "Gary Glitter", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59f4730dcfb6472aeed499d4", "question": "How many Yahtzee \"bonus\" boxes are on a Yahtzee Score Card?", "answer": "3", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6f7", "question": "Which is the largest state in the US?", "answer": "Alaska", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1bd", "question": "How old was John Lennon when he was murdered?", "answer": "40", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067e7aff9c0647b50a807b", "question": "Who was awarded the 2016 Nobel Prize for Literature?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe5", "question": "Who did George Bush Sr. defeat in the election in 1988?", "answer": "Michael Dukakis", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e49", "question": "What did Ignatz Mouse enjoy throwing at Krazy Kat's head?", "answer": "A brick", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600f71d5a9e54d890926f6e6", "question": "What Texas National Park is larger than the state of Rhode Island?", "answer": "Big Bend National Park -- Established in 1935, it is located along the Rio Grande River in southern Texas\u2019s Chihuahuan Desert.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7c3", "question": "How many US states have names which are only four letters long?", "answer": "3 - Iowa, Ohio and Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339029", "question": "Which very famous mystery novel was written by Gaston Leroux?", "answer": "The Phantom of the Opera\u00a0", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a133", "question": "What is the name of Olive Oyl's brother?", "answer": "Castor Oyl", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339061", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Samson Agonistes\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a899b4160d398dc9cf7a69b", "question": "Egg Fu is the enemy of what superhero?", "answer": "Wonder Woman", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b994", "question": "How many different railroads can be bought in the game of Monopoly?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecca43ec223966ae8f8898", "question": "Paul D. Hubbard is the quarterback who is credited with inventing the modern huddle. What affliction did he suffer from?", "answer": "He was deaf and created the huddle so that he can hear teammates better and hide plays from the defending squad.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ec", "question": "What was the name of Esther Rolles\u2019 character on both the TV shows \"Maude\" and \"Good Times\"?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fedd8836ce05a3942286d6f", "question": "A silhouette of which player is widely recognized as the inspiration behind the official NBA logo designed in 1969?", "answer": "Jerry West", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b1", "question": "Who played the female lead role in the 2007 movie \"Stardust\"?", "answer": "Claire Danes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba04", "question": "When do Americans celebrate Thanksgiving?", "answer": "Fourth Thursday in November", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc0", "question": "What is the \"Big Mac\" that was built in Michigan in 1957?", "answer": "The Mackinac Bridge", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fc856c1abc30a8194e188b3", "question": "Who was piloting the Enola Gay when it dropped the atomic bomb on Hiroshima?", "answer": "The bombardier, Tom Ferebee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ec", "question": "What year was the third iteration of the video game series \"Gran Turismo\" released?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fde4d76c6c6b019850c9a80", "question": "In the \"Book of Malachi\", God says that he has left the kingdom of Esau to which animals?", "answer": "Jackals", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd1d", "question": "Bhakti, hatha, and kriya are all varieties of what?", "answer": "Yoga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "596dffa09616e6c6d4eba4fe", "question": "Which US Holiday is celebrated on October 12th?", "answer": "Columbus Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdae", "question": "What word for mud bricks comes to us from the ancient Egyptian word \"dbt\"?", "answer": "Adobe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071dcf3745b36be73039de", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe52bc11bf59ab7d2e38104", "question": "With what skill did Odysseus defeat Penelope\u2019s suitors?", "answer": "Archery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ecf", "question": "Whose last book was \"Oh, the Places You'll Go\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss'", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff7c2c42b316f4693fb67a3", "question": "American supermarket chain Whole Foods is owned by which mega company?", "answer": "Amazon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea46ffff048f679a45aba7", "question": "What does \"PO\" stand for on a prescription?", "answer": "By mouth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b69901dd7bf43be5e7df", "question": "Which NBA player is responsible for the trend of longer basketball shorts?", "answer": "Michael Jordan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acd3", "question": "What was the official US name for the 1991 Gulf War?", "answer": "Operation Desert Storm", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea42efff048f679a45ab7d", "question": "What are poults?", "answer": "Baby turkeys", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58dba5e4874c93a3298b2154", "question": "What is formed when light is bent by layers of hot air?", "answer": "A mirage", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397bf", "question": "What does Marilyn Monroe say are a \"girl's best friend\" in Gentlemen Prefer Blondes?", "answer": "Diamonds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ec", "question": "How many US states end with the letter \"O\"?", "answer": "Four", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6cf", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Yellowhammer State\"?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c032", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cdaa5e347d002c297e4d5", "question": "What nationality is Yehudi Menuhin?", "answer": "American", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8d5", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Yukon river?", "answer": "US", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59f9b82c364247bf200fb87c", "question": "For which game was the Steam Workshop service created to allow players to share modifications?", "answer": "Team Fortress 2", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34d", "question": "The strength of prescription eyeglasses is measured in what unit?", "answer": "Diopters", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339312", "question": "In the diner scene from the movie \"When Harry Met Sally\", what did Meg Ryan order?", "answer": "Chef salad and apple pie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a94", "question": "Who had a flying carpet?", "answer": "Aladdin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59e803a9de59ea584496fe9e", "question": "What was another name for Dodie Smith's \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\" novel?", "answer": "The Great Dog Robbery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bfe", "question": "The choreographer of the movie \"High School Musical\" previously choreographed what popular 1987 movie?", "answer": "Dirty Dancing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339209", "question": "What is the four-letter name of the groundhog in Groundhog Day?", "answer": "Phil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc88", "question": "In what US city do all three of the pro sports franchises use the same two main team colors?", "answer": "Pittsburgh", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c114", "question": "What year was Canadian figure skater, Elvis Stojko, born?", "answer": "1972", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c761", "question": "Mycology is the study of what?", "answer": "Fungi", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca8", "question": "Who kicked last-second field goals to win two different Super Bowls?", "answer": "Adam Vinateri", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0b7", "question": "What is the more common name for grape sugar?", "answer": "Glucose", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff3d0364f032c0db195b498", "question": "Who were the five claimants to the Emperor of Rome in \"The Year of the Five Emperors\"?", "answer": "Pertinax, Didius Julianus, Pescennius Niger, Clodius Albinus and Septimius Severus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a4b", "question": "What celebrity showed up for a court appearance in 2005 wearing pajama bottoms?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab6a", "question": "What was Banlgadesh formerly known as until its independence?", "answer": "East Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0bf", "question": "What famous chemist died in 1934 from a blood disease contracted by the effects of radiation exposure?", "answer": "Marie Curie", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff0b36ae662d71a53650fdf", "question": "Which famous composer continued working as he lost his hearing?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe7cffe877e98cb97778a59", "question": "What island is located in The Bay of Naples?", "answer": "Capri", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58ab1430baab681b09292171", "question": "What country is home to the automobile manufacturer ZAZ?", "answer": "Ukraine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8b", "question": "In what city did NBA star LeBron James play his high school basketball home games?", "answer": "Akron, Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a90620565ad31a57c7fb", "question": "Who shot Lee Harvey Oswald?", "answer": "Jack Ruby", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfcae9dc5ec6cd98a831e", "question": "What artist's work was involved in a case before the New York Supreme Court in 2010?", "answer": "Julie Mehretu's\u00a0work was the object of a case which involved legal issues over her work and the right of first refusal contracts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133918d", "question": "Which is the only one of the Seven Dwarfs without a beard?", "answer": "Dopey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be5e", "question": "What North American Soccer League team signed Pele in 1975?", "answer": "The New York Cosmos", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea45e4ff048f679a45ab9b", "question": "Dimples on golf balls help increase speed by reducing what?", "answer": "Drag", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339628", "question": "What Canadian singer appeared on the first cover of \"Entertainment Weekly\"?", "answer": "K.D. Lang", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339850", "question": "How many legs does the catbus have in \"My Neighbour Totoro\"?", "answer": "12", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4cefbde8045e48466a2", "question": "How long is an African elephant's gestation period?", "answer": "22 months -- At birth, the calves can weigh about 250 pounds and drink up to three gallons of their mother's milk per day.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b23aed98f1a2238a7cb2b3e", "question": "What two countries noticed that they had the same flag at the 1936 Olympics in Berlin?", "answer": "Haiti and Liechtenstein", "category": "history"}]